Steven McKinnon

07753232305 <u>hello@stevenmckinnon.co.uk</u> 3/2 71 White Street, Glasgow, G11 5EF

Online résumé: http://stevemckinnon.co.uk

Profile

Highly focused, enthusiastic software developer with over 4 years experience in the financial sector. Strong team working and communication skills; including a high level of comfort when it comes to working with, and understanding business and technical requirements from end users.

Experience

LEAD FRONT END DEVELOPER, JP MORGAN CHASE - 2018-PRESENT

Currently working to build modern and responsive web applications with the end-user in mind. Working with the UX team to host usability sessions to determine end-user's expectations and needs. Building React component library for other development teams in the firm to use. Training team members up on front end technologies.

TECH LEAD, JP MORGAN CHASE - 2016-2018

Full stack developer with other responsibilities including: discussing business requirements with end users on a global scale, making design decisions for the project, handling deployments and maintaining stability of application environments, and working with, and managing Scrum and agile methodologies. Training new team members.

FRONT END DEVELOPER, JP MORGAN CHASE - 2014-2016

Key point of contact for designing (using wireframes and proof of concepts) and implementing UI/UX to meet end user needs.

Education

Computer Games Software Development (BSc Hons) • September 2010 - May 2014

Skills

I have experience with the following technologies/frameworks:

- JavaScript
- GraphQL
- Java
- Oracle SQL
- React
- MongoDB
- HTML5
- Photoshop
- CSS
- Jest / Enzyme

Interests

Music - I enjoy playing both the guitar and the drums. Both of which I have been playing since 2004. I was a member of a band playing live concerts and recording original material.

Photography - I am currently a freelance photographer working mainly in portrait, fashion, and sports work. This requires me to manage my own website, social media accounts, manage finances, and work with clients independently.

Wrestling - I was previously a student at the Glasgow Pro Wrestling Asylum. This required a lot of physical ability, mental focus, and discipline.

References

Available upon request.